01, so I
will call the meeting to order.
Then I see we've got Scott Persson here,
Steve Nelson.
I do not see
Anne Cremay.
So I will see Kevin
for Anne.
And I'm going through I
will also see
Anne Blanchard.
And then with myself that that
rounds out the board.
So item three addition changes to the agenda. Does anybody have any additional
hope I see and cremate just
showed
>> up. Okay.
Yeah.
So I will
unseat Kevin, who I think I put in for Anne.
So the
voting members
for the time being are myself, Scott Persson, Steve Nelson,
Anne Blanchard and Anne Creme.
I
think Leanne's here, Jed.
>> am. Can you hear me? Oh, I can hear you now, Leanne. Okay. So
then,
Ian Blanchard is unseated and we have Leanne here.
Sorry about that.
>> Okay, we're on.
Abby, did you get all those changes to who's seated? We're back to our
five actual commission members are all present now.
I got it. Yep. Okay.
>> Item three, addition or changes to the agenda? And I have none.
Jim, were
you able to get ahold of Chris Bell? Was he
>> playing I any
a message on his phone.
I did not speak to him. Okay.
>> Is part of our
discussion tonight,
Chris Bell may pop in and give us an update
on what's going on at the gravel pit. We're trying to
sort that out.
But we'll put that in as part of our discussion.
Item four is members for public comment. Are there any members of the public
that
are not here for a specific agenda item that have any other comments to share with the Commission at this point?
And I don't think there are. I think I know why everybody's here. So we will move on to item five,
whole business, the sign regulations.
I just wanted to say on that that
Jim and I met with attorney Branch
a week or so ago
and
went over. We had a discussion about the sign regulations.
He's out trying to update those for us. He thought maybe he would have those for us by now, but I didn't get them from him. So I couldn't send them out, but those will be coming along at some point soon.
Whole business 5B, the affordable housing plan.
We're in the process of getting the contract signed with Bill Warner.
And I expect he had a couple of unexpected
losses
on his town where
he's
working with the
town planner,
and so he's going to get a little bit of a late start there. I expect him to join us for our December meeting
to hold a kickoff on that, and
we'll really get going hot and heavy in the affordable housing plan after the first of the year.
And going on to 5C legislative
update,
Jim, I can't remember if you wanted to say something on that
or not.
>> I really didn't. I just
wanted to keep it on the agenda
for just sort of an ongoing basis,
or at least until
we
sort out what happened in the last legislative session.
I am
trying to figure out what's going on as far as
cannabis, cannabis law,
as I know you are, Jed.
I don't have anything in particular, no, at this time.
>> Okay.
And Jim, I saw an email from you that indicated that maybe you had the journal inquiry article from Saturday's paper on cannabis?
I did.
>> I could get a copy of that.
Sure. I wouldn't mind reading through it. I don't get the journal inquiry, so I don't have it. But I heard it had a lot of good stuff in there.
Anyhow, that's it for old business. We're going to move on to new business. And the first
item is
the application
2103,
Korean Lateszka
Subdivision special permit.
And the action item is request for filing extension
And
discussion item, request for minor modification proof subdivision plan. So,
George, I didn't see Eric here, so I assume you're doing the discussion on the filing extension.
Yes. So we are requesting an
extension of time.
Civil engineer
>> slash surveyor
Andrew Bushnell is still working on our,
our project, and
we weren't able to quite make the I don't think that we're going to make the ninety day
time limit.
>> Okay,
yep. And
I know we voted
to approve that application at the June meeting. So I know we're getting fairly close.
And I've been talking to Jim, he said you were having some issues with the utilities in
there.
Yes.
You have
do you know how long an extension you think you're gonna need?
>> I'm not quite sure, to be honest with you.
We're sort of at the mercy of
other people.
So I don't know exactly how long. Think in my mind, if we were granted
another few months, I think that we can do that.
>> For the record, the applicable section of the state
statutes allows for up
to two ninety day extensions.
So I would suggest to stay with the ninety days.
The way I read it is you apply for ninety, and if that doesn't work, you ask for another ninety.
It
wasn't up to ninety, it was ninety days. And just
to refresh anybody's memory,
the special permit component is
George's application
involved
two rear lots,
which required
special permit
as part of the subdivision.
That's why they're both there.
>> Okay.
When we get
around to taking action, we'll talk about a ninety day extension, just keeping clean with that. Yes.
And George, because I happen to be a member of the Wetlands
Commission as well, I know that you discussed
with
Agent Wagner
the
modifications
to
the
culvert, the box culvert that was going to be put in for the
driveway.
And can you lead the commission through that? Because,
know, one
of the things that we have to do with
the change
to whatever plan we approved
is we have to make a decision as to whether or not it's a substantive plan
or an insignificant
change in the plan
and take
action that way. If it's
a rather insignificant change as determined by the commission,
we can allow our agent
Halsey to
adjudicate that with you. If it's deemed that that's a significant change from the original application,
then we have to go through the process
over again. And that's just the way our instructions
are written out on how we handle those changes.
So if you can brief the Commission on
why it is that we're changing
the box culvert, I'd appreciate that. Sure. So our original
>> plan we submitted on a four sided
box culvert
where we were going to
have the driveway go over the top of the culvert
and we would use native materials
from the wetland area to create a new
invert for the water to flow through underneath the driveway.
Unfortunately for us,
there's been
more price increasing on
on the box culvert.
It's gotten to the point now where it's
almost out of reach for us.
So I looked into an all terrier or
an alternate method.
And that would be a three sided culvert.
It's an open bottom three sided culvert.
In going with this route,
we would do most of the work ourselves. Basically, we would be casting in place the
culvert and
we would not be disturbing the natural invert that's there now. The natural water flow invert
would remain,
and we would actually build over it.
In my opinion, this is less
invasive
into the wetlands.
And it would be a tremendous cost savings for us.
>> So when I looked at
the drawing that I saw, and I can't remember if that was on our website or the Inland Wetlands at this point,
It looked like there was
a foundation
to be
dug into the wetlands
the side of the two
upward sides would
go into?
>> Yes, so if you look at the drawing there, we would excavate
down below frost depth
on both sides of the natural invert.
So we would dig down about three feet.
At the bottom there, you see that there is a
it's a it's a spread footing. It's basically a footing like you would use
in building a house.
From there, we would build a wall on top of that.
That wall would be probably
it'll be about five feet tall, five and a half feet tall.
And then we would build a slab on top of that.
This this drawing here has been designed by a structural engineer
to meet the h 20 load rating that
Brandon requested
and requires.
So essentially,
they would be they would there would be three pores.
We would cast the footings,
we would then form and cast the wall,
both walls,
and then we would
form and cast
the cap or the top.
>> Okay, and I
think it is
still a true statement that you have not gotten the wetlands approval for the change
in the driveway construction yet?
That's the truth. Okay, so,
>> at this point,
the first,
I'd like to make a motion that we approve the ninety day extension
to the filing of the drawings
that's requested
by the applicant.
Second that. I'll second
>> Leanne. Okay, thank you, Leanne. And
any discussion on that issue?
Okay, hearing none,
a call for a roll call vote to
Scott Person.
Aye.
Anne Gremay?
>> Leanne?
Aye.
Steve?
And I vote aye as well. That motion passes five zero zero.
I
guess I will make a motion
that
the request for the minor modification
to the approved subdivision plan
be considered a minor modification
and turned over to Agent Halsey for adjudication with the applicant.
Second.
>> Okay, thank you, Steve.
And so is there any discussion
on that particular motion?
And again,
know, Agent Halsey can't do anything until it's gotten
wetlands
approval.
And I would also expect agent Halsey to touch base with our engineer just to make sure he agrees with
the changes that are made.
>> Yeah, Chairman Larson Hallisey, I just wanted to point something out just to refresh people's memories. One
of the conditions of the approval of the subdivision was
that our tunnel engineer
approved the final design
or final specs on that culvert.
So there is a condition
in place already, but just
pointing that out.
This further just
enforces
that.
Okay.
Any other discussion on
the second motion?
>> The first,
yeah, we can talk about this, right, Chad? Yes,
absolutely.
>> The first approval was
through wetlands, there was no excavating,
it was all
filling
as I remember.
Now there's going to be excavating in the,
correct?
The wetlands?
>> If
we would still have to do excavation
in order to install the four sided culvert,
there's actually less excavation
required to do a three sided than it would be to do the four sided.
>> Well now you have to dig below frost, put a footing,
so that's four feet.
The other one you're just moving the material,
flattening it out.
No,
>> we would have to, we would be digging down
two to three feet,
the
full dimension
of the box covert
in order for us to place native materials back into the box covert
to maintain the natural
water flow invert.
>> The old drawing said it was one foot below grade to
>> the bottom of the box. Right. That's what I remember. But it has to sit on a foot of stone.
But okay.
I
didn't see the subsurface and the plan last time.
>> So there is, there's going to be substantially more excavation than
the prior application.
And you're
gonna pour this
in one piece and you're gonna pour it yourself?
>> Yeah, it's not in one piece. It's gonna be three pores.
>> I know what, no, the deck. Yeah. The deck.
Yes.
The deck is gonna be poured in one piece. Yes.
Does the wetlands know Jed did you go to that meeting?
>> I did go to that meeting and
I don't,
we did not have,
the applicant was not present at that meeting and so we didn't have opportunity
to
address what the changes were and Agent Wagner,
I don't know that he had the drawing that we just looked at
to describe to the wetlands group
what was going to happen. And that's why we
deferred that action to the following meeting
where we expect,
you know, one of the applicants there to address the questions of the Commission.
Right. So now you're gonna be digging 42 plus
a foot for material
below it.
>> No.
If
the footing can sit on undisturbed
native soil.
It is?
The footing can, yes.
>> I thought it just said in the
document that it was going to be 42 inches in the ground.
>> Yes,
so the bottom of the footing would be 42 inches. Yeah.
Okay.
Jed, can you bring that print back up?
>> I think
Abby was the person who displayed that. So Abby, can you bring that back up to the drawing? Yep.
Hold on just a second.
What was the total length of the culvert?
21 feet. Okay.
>> So you'll probably need to remove some material in the middle so that you can get all the formwork back out after the pour, right?
>> No, I don't plan on that. I plan to dig.
So that footing there's see 23,000
>> only have a two foot window to work in right.
I'm sorry, say it again. Like you only have a two foot window to so you'd have to like crawl, you know, lay Yeah, we would dig the
footing. The excavation would be about four feet wide.
>> But you'd need to take soil out of the middle to get your forms out, unless you're gonna leave the forms in place after you're done, right?
>> No, there would be enough space so we can maneuver the forms out of place. The
intent is to leave
the natural invert intact.
>> Okay, are there any other questions for the applicant at this point? Where where's the grade on this
map, this document?
I don't I don't believe the grade is
>> the yeah, the grade is not depicted on this
drawing. This drawing is
solely for the construction of the culvert.
>> But we know
the grade was fairly much level when you get down to the bottom
where
>> the stream's running through there. Yeah, if you were to highlight
a little bit more on the footing,
there's a dimension that's given there from the bottom of footing to proposed
final grade,
which is three foot
six.
So the grade is there at three six?
>> That's just what that number has given you is the
is what the engineer is
requesting
for a bottom of footing from the finished grade.
>> Jim Jim Halsey,
have you ever had a footing put
on grade?
>> Give me a second here.
I
mean, frost protection is 42 inches under building code for for residential structures. Okay? Is that I mean, that's where this
I don't know if I'm assuming
this is where the 42 inches comes from. The quest my I don't I'm not trying to avoid your question. Have I ever had a a footing
put
on grade?
No. Not that I recall. No. I mean,
structures are placed placed on grade.
Garages are dropped on,
for instance,
sheds, garages are dropped on paths or stone,
but there's no footing involved.
Did I answer your question or did I avoid it? No, there's
>> no
footing, there's no footings, no modern footings. The only footing that wasn't put on grade is a haunched footing.
It's an old style footing, they don't use them anymore. It always has to be below grade.
Any footing has to be below grade.
Footing this
>> is going to be below grade also, it has to be. You can't put a bridge
above on grade
unless I'm missing something here.
>> The footing is three foot six below final grade.
The bottom of footing
is 42 inches
from the finished
grade.
>> Okay so
there you go right? So you're so you're going to be digging then?
Yes.
Right and
on the last application there was no digging was going to be put on just a little bit on the stream bed that was it.
Then the
whole structure was going be put down, the stuff was going to be put back underneath the bridge.
That's all I'm trying to get at here. You're going to be digging substantially
more, 20 feet wide and you know three six deep minimum plus there's going to be more material underneath the group that structure because you can't put it on
native soil, native
material.
So,
it's going to be you know a
foot every every footing is always put on you know around a foot of material.
>> But I think that's an issue for the Wetlands Commission
to decide upon.
Yeah. And that it will be reviewed by our engineer to make sure that it's structurally sound.
And one of the options is we can hold the decision on this item in abeyance till
next month. Sounds like we're not going be ready to start construction.
You know, we're asking for another
couple of month delay to get the
documents signed
to start the project,
so I don't know that
it's the end of the world if we wait until the November meeting to decide on this.
I wanted to make a motion so that we could have the discussion that we're having now.
>> Well, if we approve this, our
engineer still has to review it and approve it and Wetlands has to deal with it as well, right? Yes, Wetlands needs to
>> agree to
this before
the Commission or
our zoning agent would be able to act on It has
to be beyond
that point.
Right.
So the question is,
do we allow
Agent Halsey to do that after Wetlands has approved it
and the engineer has agreed to it?
Or do we want that decision to come back to the Commission?
And so the
discussion the the motion was to make
to consider it
a minor change
where it would be handled by
the zoning agent
after Wetlands approves it
and the
engineer
concurs in the design.
And we can wait another month to make that decision as to whether or not we give that to Jim.
Certainly the discussion
has
indicated that it's not a trivial matter to
put those foundation
supports in there.
Although I do think that on the same note,
if you were to do
a total volume
removed to support the construction,
I
don't know that George would be wrong in saying that there's less this way.
Certainly,
one is not
way out of bounds with respect
to the other. So,
you know, I think it's probably
fairly close either way you cut it. It's about the same disturbance of wetlands.
One might be a little deeper, one might be a lot wider,
and so
how that comes out, I'll take George's word for it, that it comes out to be less disturbance
in the wetlands.
But that's for the wetlands agency to go off and take a look at.
So,
I worded,
as I will always word motions,
in the positive
because if we were to make
a
negative motion and then the negative motion failed,
we don't know where that puts us.
Is there any commission discussion before we vote
as to whether or not we should hold off? Well, I guess I'll ask George first.
That do you think
if we were to vote on this at the November meeting that would delay your
plans at any extent at this point?
I
don't think so. Yeah.
>> Is there any reason we would want to delay and have it come back here? If Wetlands approves it and the engineer approves it,
would we have any reason to have it come back?
Or can Jim just execute on the plan?
>> Only,
well, there's probably no reason to come back. The
issue would be
if we were to be
so
concerned about the change in the construction technique
that we thought that we would not have approved it had that been the original one,
and we want to disapprove the project
because of that,
then we might want to come back. But we've had a good discussion on it. I'm certainly a lot smarter on
the whole issue than I was before we had the discussion, so I'm very glad that we did have that. But I think
your comment, Steve,
is still germane that
if
it comes back to us or it goes to the zoning agent, as long as it gets
the approval of wetlands and the approval of our engineer,
I guess
that might be our concern unless you voted no on the issue of turning it over to Agent Allisi,
then we would ask
to come back for us for further discussion. But I'm not sure what
we
would gain by having further discussion on that particular issue at this point. I think we're all as smart as we need to be to
make that call.
Agreed.
Okay,
any other I discussion before we
>> have a question that may not be exactly with this, but it's got to do with the site and the drainage is
to ask
George, how did the
area fair with the big rainstorms
we had this summer since this was approved?
I was wondering, I had like a river in my backyard and I don't even have the kind of area or the hill that they have. And I was wondering if you saw
anything about how much water came through there. Does this design
carry all the, take care of all that water?
>> So
I went, we had the two big storms, and I, I went a few days after each of the big storms,
by the time.
I think after the first big storm I want I went down there two days later,
there was no more running water that down
in the low spot.
And there didn't seem to be a whole lot of
like leaves and twigs
and sticks
displaced or piled up
the place. The area didn't look really any different than it did any other time I've been down there.
And
so then we had the second big storm.
And I actually went down there the following day.
There was no running water, but it was wet. And again, wasn't
really any large displacement of leaves or piling up of sediment or anything like that.
And
actually, Andrew Bushnell went down there the day,
maybe two days after the second storm, and he was,
he had the same
opinion
as I did, you know, that it really didn't seem much different.
Which surprised me because I thought it would be,
actually,
thought I was worried after the first storm because we had so much rain
that
you know that
I didn't know what was going to happen down there to be and
so.
Okay.
>> I will go out on a limb and say I went down there the day of the big storm
because I was curious too what we were going to learn from having this significant event.
As George just said, I was surprised
by the lack of flow
through that area. I lived next to a little brook here going into
Andover Lake and it was running like I had never seen it run.
And the Hop River was
the same, but
I did not see
anything near what I thought I might see
down there.
So I was convinced that
the openings that we designed
in the driveway were
more than adequate
to handle
anything that was coming that way. And
I did all the due diligence that I could do.
So
I agree with George's assessment there.
Any other questions? Any other discussion?
Okay, and again, the motion is for us to turn over adjudication
of the issue to Agent Halsey.
And I'll start out
roll call vote with Anne.
Aye.
>> Scott?
Steve?
Aye.
Leanne?
And I vote aye as well.
The motion carries 500.
Okay, thank you, George. Good luck with getting your plans.
>> Thank you, guys. Everyone have a great night. Thank you. Next
>> item up is
request for feedback on a potential
meditation center
accessory uses at 131
Route 6.
And I think Patrick is here to
run us through a presentation on that.
>> Jed, I'll start off. Actually, we'll start. Okay.
Jed, are you able to share screen enable
screen sharing by any chance?
To have you share the screen? Yeah. Yes.
Yep, I can do that. Go ahead.
Awesome.
>> All right, you should have the ability now. Yeah, I can. Thank you. I'm just going to start off without the screen while I introduce myself. Thank you, Jed and Jim for having us here today. Jim also thank you for answering our questions and sort of all the guidance you have provided thus far.
My name is Nilakshi Parnigamagaya.
I'm a resident of Bridge Connecticut where I live with my husband and two kids.
I also serve as the Chief of Staff and an Associate Provost at the provost office at Yale.
I am here today as a community leader
associated with the Connecticut Meditation Center
and a representative of two monks, Venerable Kundanja
and Venerable Sumeda,
who are here today
as leaders of this Connecticut Meditation Center.
We call the Connecticut Meditation Center CTMC,
and we're all here today
because the CTMC is actually under contract and would like to purchase
White's Tavern,
which is located at 131
In Route 6 in Andover.
I will take a few minutes to introduce you to who we are,
describe the functions of our meditation center.
Patrick will then take over and give you a brief overview of the properties location and our current conceptual plans.
In the end, we'll have some questions for all of you and we'll have plenty of time to answer any questions or concerns you may have.
I am, as I said, joined by several of our community members here.
Let me just share my screen.
Several of our community members, including the two monks who lead our
community.
So who are we? We are
the Connecticut Meditation Center, which is a meditation
based
Buddhist temple
based in Connecticut.
Most of our members are Sri Lankan heritage,
although the center serves both Buddhist and non Buddhist communities.
We are a thriving community and have been active in Connecticut since about 2014.
And we're registered, the center is registered as a nonprofit religious organization.
Our total membership is around 150,
although I must admit we only gather as a community of about 75
to 100
no more than two times a year.
The monks who lead our community
have served us served in their leadership capacity at the Connecticut Meditation Center for many years.
They have had temporary residencies
in temples in New York and Boston all of these years,
and frequently and often visit community members in Connecticut for extended periods of time.
But there has been this great need for all of us to find a physical home located in Connecticut,
And we're very hopeful in this moment that White's Tavern might be that much needed home.
One of the reasons that it has taken us a little while to find our home is we we sort of wanted to find a community where we could respect the nature, find a community that would welcome us find a community where we could sort of be good neighbors to
each other. And so
we're very excited about White's Tavern.
The easiest way to describe how this property will be used if CTMC
purchases the property is that we will it will serve both sort of as a church and a rectory.
For the rectory part, they will be about one to three monks who will reside there.
And
Buddhist monks,
just like pastors and ministers of other religious traditions,
do not draw any wages and
our monks have been and will continue to be more than supported by the CTMC membership.
The church part of the property will
support our community activities in two ways. One, it will support our existing community,
will be a gathering place for meditation and fellowship. And it's also sort of a place where we will continue to seek the wise counsel of our monks.
But
in line with lots of Buddhist temples and gathering places, we really hope to open up the property to residents of Andover as a community gathering place as a community space where if anyone is interested, they can have communal events too.
The center will host meditation and yoga workshops and classes.
The center will not be a profit making endeavor that is sort of antithetical to our practices,
and any services
like yoga and meditation that will be offered to the larger public will be free of charge to any members in the local community.
So our center supports sort of a family based Connecticut,
a group of Connecticut residents
that are really keen to respect the environment in which Whites Tavern sits
and very eager to serve as thoughtful neighbors to all of you.
I'm happy to answer more questions about who we are at the end of the presentation,
but I'll hand it over to Patrick who
will walk you over sort of a property overview.
Great. And are we sharing screens now?
>> Can you see it? I can
walk you through the slides, Patrick.
Do you see it?
I don't.
>> Does
anyone, everyone else see it? I hope everyone else has been able to see it. I see it. Yep. Yes.
>> Okay.
Great. So we're
on the property location overview slide. And just to kind of frame the discussion here,
this is obviously
a meeting intended to gather sort of informal feedback from all of you. We have not done any detailed site planning.
Everything we present here is purely for discussion purposes.
We're looking for
feedback and advice from you all.
As we go through the process,
we're looking to hear any major concerns or roadblocks
you have.
But in order for you to give us that feedback, we wanted to
give you a good idea of what our high level intentions for the property are.
So as you you I'm sure you all know the property better than we do even it's located
at 131 Route 6.
It is in the business zoning district which
allows churches and schools and other uses
with a site plan review.
Its current use is listed as a two family residence. There are currently people
living at the residence and so we are under contract to purchase it. And I understand it's
a total of seven acres. It's not just the one parcel, but it's actually the
three parcels
together.
So the one with that blue marker is and then the two parcels
to the north of that and east of
Route 6.
Okay, so we can go to the next slide showing the conceptual plans.
They're going to see that?
Yes.
>> Yeah. Okay.
So again, this is this is purely for discussion purposes.
But basically, what we will need for the site is a place for the monks to live,
you know, for one to three months to live safely. And then we will also need a place for religious services and education.
And
for the latter use in particular, we will probably require
a new structure.
We don't know
exactly how large it would be or exactly where it would be placed. But this was just our initial thinking
was that it'd be close to the road for easy access
and to utilize the existing driveway. And then there would be parking.
And obviously, the size would have to be determined based on the
size of the temple that we built.
There are some existing accessory structures
on the property.
We are still kind of investigating those to see whether
there would be of any use
to us,
but we're still kind of
reviewing that. And we're also trying to fully understand
what is needed in terms of repair
to
White's Tavern itself.
So those are the kinds of things we're saying we're thinking of. But basically,
we're looking at a place for the monks to live and some kind of temple structure
to be located on the site and with the necessary parking to
serve that temple.
Over the very long term, perhaps we would want to build additional structures, but that's
what was our discussion for the moment.
So that is kind of an overview
what we intend to do, what we intend to use the site for.
And so our
immediate questions for the town
and I'll kind of read through these all at the same time and let you all give you all a chance to respond as first is, do you all see any
major concerns regarding this use at this location? And the context of that question is really,
we are under contract to purchase this, but if you believe there are major roadblocks to us securing approval for this, if you have any major concerns,
we would like to know that now before we close on contract,
of course.
We know that the Whites Tavern is
very old, dates to 1792.
So we want to understand if there are any obligations or restrictions that the town imposes
because of its historic nature.
And then
the two other key questions are,
if
we think this is a use that could be approved, what's the best way to do that? We've spoken with Jim about possibly approving it as a church use, which is
know, an improved use under the business district with a site plan approval.
But I understand that there may be other ways to do it
that you find appropriate. So we'd like to hear your thoughts there. And then the last
sort of key question we have is we know the site plan approval process would take some time.
And we are wondering whether
in the meantime, the monks could move into the existing residents
even before that site plan would be approved.
So maybe there I'll stop and
give you all a chance to answer some of those questions.
>> So do any of the commission members have any comments
at this point?
>> Did the government put any restrictions on
its uses or you know changes
when they
deemed it the White Tavern?
I wonder if there is any I'm sure that you know the busks went through you know, ten years of trying to get it onto that historic,
I don't know what you would call it, but
I'm wondering if there is any restrictions about what you can, what the changes that you can make to it or whatever.
I don't know. I'd be happy to address that.
Yeah. Go ahead, Jim.
>> Halsey, as
far as I'm not exactly sure what designation it has,
but assuming it's
on the National Registry,
there are really
no restrictions per se. The registry designation mostly comes into play as far as
making it eligible for tax credits. There are certain types of
use, usually it's commercial use.
Other than that, I mean, does
give somebody
should
folks
standing
should they
choose to
take
issue on it under the
Connecticut Environmental Protection Act, which gives
anybody
standing in case against it for historic preservation issues.
But no, there's nothing, no
federal money was used in it which would have triggered covenants of restriction
or anything of that nature.
So I'd say no.
>> Good. And I'll just say we did
speak with
her name is Jane Schofield at the State
Historical
Preservation
Department. That's not the exact name, but she indicated that it was listed on the National Registered Store Places and the State Registered Store Places,
which enabled it to receive tax credits, but that
there were no restrictions or obligations placed on the owner because of that.
>> In fact, the section of our regulation section 4.15,
historic
preservation
by way of adaptive historic reuse.
It seems to be very liberal
in
what it would allow. It talks about allowing for things
outside of what would normally be allowed
in
whatever district it's in. And so
I think
that
invoking that particular article, which would require the special permit
with the public hearing,
probably gives you the most latitude
in
the way to go there.
But I saw no roadblocks.
>> Steve, you had a comment? Well, I was wondering, even if there are no roadblocks
or restrictions,
is there any intent to preserve
any
of the history
that's relevant
to the site?
>> So I think we can say we would absolutely
respect the
Whites Tavern and we have no intention to
demolish it or anything.
I think the only issue there is
cost,
right? And we haven't fully investigated it. So,
you know, we can't commit to anything per se.
But I can certainly say we have no
you know, if it's in our power, we will certainly not do anything to harm White Statham, I think is the short answer.
But beyond that, you know, until we have better idea of what the costs would be,
you know, I wouldn't want to commit to anything.
>> How
many parking spaces were you gonna put in there?
>> So that was a
We don't know. And that's partly a question for you all. I know that the zoning regulations said
for a church use that it would be
something like one space for every three seats.
In truth, until we actually size the building,
we won't really know.
So,
but I guess I would say, that's something that we would discuss
with you and Jim and make sure that we're providing the appropriate amount of parking for the people that would be visiting.
>> The entrance would be off of Route 6 or Hutchinson Road or both?
What where was the access
to that parking space?
>> If I understand it, the
just looking at the map, the the driveway connects between Hutchinson Road and Route 6 would be accessible from both.
Okay. Again, I
say that as,
you know, if there's a problem with that, we can change it because we're,
you know, nothing is set in stone at this point.
>> Any
other
comments or questions from any other commission members?
>> Hi, this is Leanne. I have a comment and a question or two.
Yeah, go ahead Leanne.
>> I think it was Mr. Lynch, could you just repeat your answer, I guess I didn't quite catch it, to the last question from Scott Person about whether or not you would have,
people entering from Route 6 or Hutchinson Road or both.
>> So
the short answer is if there's a concern from the town, either way, we would respect that. I think as we look at it now that there's a driveway connecting Hutchinson Road and Route 6. So from our standpoint,
they could enter from both
or either road, which whatever is preferable to the town. We have not we really haven't gotten that far in the site planning process to give you a more definitive answer.
>> Okay, thank That
side of the property is the driest side. The other side is wet,
very wet that
towards the east it's very wet. The other side to the north is dry.
>> That are you talking about in terms of the driveway?
>> I'm talking about where they they proposed
to put the parking lot. It's a lot drier on that side. They decided that they proposed to put it on it. It's a better location. Yeah.
>> Okay.
Thank you. And then I have under immediate questions for the town, I have a couple of questions about number four. It says, could we begin work on making an existing structure habitable before the site plan approval is granted?
I guess I have a kind of a two part question. I don't
know much about real estate, but when you say you have a closing in a couple of days,
because this
proposal seems to have
a couple of different aspects. One is the house that would be used as a residence. And I don't think other than number of people in the house, which isn't an issue, that we can tell you who can live in the house. So, I think you could, if you go through with the purchase,
go ahead and
make
improvements or, you know, make it habitable,
depending on what it looks like on the inside now,
as a home for the MUC.
So, are you going to go I this is I don't know if the Commission is planning to take this beyond tonight or if we're going to need to.
I guess I'm just wondering if you're going to go ahead after the twentieth,
depending on what we do tonight. And I guess the second part of my question is
and I'm asking the Commission because I don't know
I don't know because we don't have this come up, where someone asks to put,
you know, a church
or religious building on a site like this. I'm just asking.
I don't know that this has ever come up before.
>> So the last part of your second question, Leanne, was about putting a church on a piece of property like this?
Yes, I'm just asking. I'm not speaking
either way.
>> Yep. No, all I can tell you is
that, as Patrick said,
the
church is one of the allowable
uses
by site
plan
in a business district.
So it
has to be
allowable.
If there was a question before that on item two, I don't remember what it was, but I think it
is allowed by our regulations.
>> So it sounds like all we would have jurisdiction over is the amount of people in the parking area.
>> Yes, and you know, it
sounds like
Patrick's done his homework,
saw our section 12 on parking there,
and I think you're based on
the number of 120
people that he had listed,
that
would, by our
little chart,
anywhere from a low of 24 parking spots to a maximum of 40
is what I think comes out for that. So
there's,
you you've to go lay it all out, but you make it big enough to
accommodate
all that, and I think you're in business.
>> Okay. Thank you. So I guess just my only other question for clarification regarding what you just said about having a church on the property is,
so we're not mentioning any constraints right now. Again, I'm asking. I'm not suggesting anything because that is part of what they would like for feedback.
Since they would do that in the future, would we just address that separately at the time or
would we be doing that tonight?
>> Well, think the
intention tonight
in
the applicants can correct me if I'm wrong. Well, they aren't applicants yet. We don't have an application.
They're interested in purchasing the property. And I think they've got until
the twentieth to make a decision on whether or not
they want to make an offer is the way I understand it. Actually, have until Friday.
I we have until Friday
>> listed that by accident. That's my internal deadline to make the decision, but Friday, this Friday. Okay. Yeah. So if there was something that we saw that said, nope, it just ain't going to work,
they'd be interested in hearing that from us tonight.
I think
for me personally and a lot of the other commission members, this is the first
time we've looked at zoning
regulations
in regards to
all these different aspects.
And so that
doesn't mean we're, that means that I'm not real familiar with how it's all going to play out, but I can't see anything that stands in the way of getting to the finish line
one way or another. You know, you with a land use engineer or whatever would have to determine
which of the different articles in our regulations that you want to
peruse, and it's probably going to be your portions of each
so that we're complying with everything. Obviously, the town would like White's Tavern
to stay. That's a pretty historic
structure.
If you were to, I guess my
question,
reading through the historic section, that article 4.15
talks about any other buildings
being
constructed on the property
be somewhat consistent
with the historic nature of the tavern.
And I'm not exactly sure what a Buddhist temple looks like, but I'm not sure how
we could blend the two to make it look like a historic New England
building?
That is a very question,
>> Jed. If you were to go to a Sri Lankan village and ask what Buddhist temple looks like it'll be something very different in this instance it will be just a New England home
a place where the monks would reside would they have a community kitchen it would just resemble
a home It would have an area like a large living room or if we ever sometime down the line have a second structure a gathering space where about 2,030
folks can gather and engage in fellowship or talk to the monks.
Architecturally
there's,
there's nothing
unusual
in the plans and as I said, one of the reasons we really like this location was also there's so much nature and it's sort of unobtrusive
existence is sort of part of the philosophy of
our community. So I can I there are a few things I can guarantee about so many of these things just because everything is such conceptual planning but I can guarantee you that it's not going to be sort of an eyesore of any any sort? The goal is to blend in and
be good supportive neighbors and nothing
less. Yeah,
>> so as
I understand it, the idea is that for the tavern, which is a residence now,
to be a residence for the monks,
and then you would build the
gathering
place or the temple
that would be the new building that you would be putting on the site.
>> That is currently the plan depending on how this approval process works and sort of fundraising and what our eventual plans are. What we definitely don't anticipate any massive structures. It will be either
White's Tavern as the rectory and a separate space for a church,
like a large gathering hall with the kitchen and bathrooms.
That is currently the plan.
Again, we haven't done
a ton of digging into the state of White's Tavern and what it would take to
get it up to a certain level, but that's absolutely the goal. Okay. Now,
>> the other
thing in line
with that is if we had a site plan
that
included
a
temple on it,
the expectation is that the temple would be built.
One of the things
that
in discussing how, you know, with our attorney, how to proceed
with this,
the question came up,
so
if we don't have the temple building constructed
and we're just
looking at the use of White's Tavern to be the facility,
how much of the facility is the
church and what
portion of the facility is the residence,
thinking that if it's going to be a church,
the church would have a bigger
footprint
than the living spaces.
I'm not sure that the tavern
is conducive to that at this point, but that was one of the things that
should come into the consideration
for
our determination of what it is that we are approving.
>> Fair question. So the site plan would include this other structure and the goal absolutely is to have a second structure. We the White's Tavern by itself would not suffice in the longer term
as both a church and a rectory. It's very much a home.
And so
it's a matter of what is our timeline and get it getting breaking ground and getting the construction going. So I might ask a question from you when you say, know, if you approve a site plan that has a temple, will a temple be built? The answer to that is absolutely yes. Is there a concern about timeline? Do we have to break ground immediately? Is it sort of a, know, within six months? That's the part that I can't 100% guarantee just yet, but maybe once we get into the site planning process, we'll have a little bit more clarity.
>> Okay, Agent Halsey, I know you went through some extensions
to
site plans
and special permits for our previous discussion there.
All I'm familiar with is what our regulations
require,
and it talks about,
you know, if construction
isn't completed,
I'm thinking it says within a year,
you know, the
approval is null and void.
>> Would assume That's two years, but I would like to double Okay, check
yep.
>> But is there a way to extend that
in the case of building the second
structure
on that as well or would you have to go
>> and get that? I'm going to have to look into that. I don't
recall.
I would hope that there's some flexibility.
I would hope so too.
>> I
would like to point out one issue. I know that folks are looking for as
much information as you can. One thing that will in all probability be required by the Department of Transportation
is a change of use
because Route 6 is obviously a state road.
I don't have any reason to believe that's prohibitive.
Just don't throw it out there.
>> And what was that, Jim? You said a change of use? Change of use from
>> the either the state traffic Commissioner DOT.
I would assume when it would be required.
Okay. To operate
a
religious.
>> Jed, they have they they have an actual application in right now or just a plan? There is no application. This is the pre NDA The
plan is a temple
has a temple written on it. I saw that. Right? Yes. Yep. So I mean right now if they took the temple
off of that, all we would be is okaying is the
use as a
residence for the three monks
and at a later date they could come back and
give us another
drawing with maybe an application when they're ready to do the rest of it.
>> But I'm sure that they would like
before they invest in the property to understand that we would
be
favorable
to having, you know, they don't want to go move into the tavern and then find out they can't
build the temple there. They want to know, you know,
I think that they're good to go for
the whole plan.
And again, there's got to be flexibility that we can build in that somehow with
extensions,
everything gets built in a day, but. Right, yeah.
>> I mean, residential use is currently a use of right
right
in the business section of the zoning regs,
which is any structure in existence or any residence in existence at the time of adoption of this reg, which is circa 1970
or sometime in the seventies, is a use of is a use of right. It's not a nonconforming use. It is a use of right. They certainly have enough property so.
>> Yep. I don't see any reason why a temple couldn't be built there but if it's a big hang up tonight.
>> Nope, I agree with you Scott.
Patrick, did you have any
further slides that you wanted to go through with us?
Let me just share the last slide.
>> Yeah, I think we've touched on most of it.
I think the other questions,
maybe we've touched on all these already, but
would there be any additional or specific requirements
because of educational activities? We would have some classes there. It'd be something similar to Sunday school, but also for adults.
And
I spoke with Jim about this earlier, but there are some smaller sort of accessory structures on the property, which, you know, we don't know the state of that. We don't know whether they're of any use at all. We didn't know whether there would be any problems with removing them,
assuming that, you know, we determined to have no use.
>> Okay. I would like to address you you're
asking a number of questions
regarding
fire marshal, etcetera. I mean, it would fall in building code questions. I mean, this, I assume, would fall under
assembly use,
which triggers a number of requirements, which I'm not prepared to you know, they fall outside the realm of the commission.
But,
you know, there certainly there certainly are requirements,
and,
you know, you're obviously trying to get a better hit you know, a handle on on everything you can here, and
that's something
an architect is probably in the best
position to answer.
I try Right. To go to the fire marshal and say without
a plan, you know, and say what are the requirements. Yep.
>> Again,
those are all good questions and yes, the answer to all of them is probably yes.
We've got requirements for all those things.
But again, it's all fairly straightforward.
Don't understand.
>> Anything that would come as a surprise to you that
and so that's
all
secondary.
Yes, you're going to have to go through
all these issues here,
again, as far as the big picture of
living in the tavern
and
building a temple,
I can see
nothing that gets in the way other than picking the path you want to follow to get there.
>> Right, and
so that leads me on to, I guess the last question is,
in terms of picking a path,
should we do that in consultation with a land planner
and perhaps in conversations
with
zoning agent Jim?
Is that the best way forward for us? I'm assuming today you're not going to decide on what the whether it should be a church or an adapter for use or or one of these other options. You're going to need a surveyor,
>> a wetlands
guy,
and then an engineer to engineer your whole
plan, know.
But it's like Jed said, it's not going to be a big deal. These
are all standard things that we deal with every meeting.
>> So with that, and I know one of the questions was, so what is the way ahead?
Generally,
we wait,
so you put in an application
and then
the Commission would normally come out and we do a site visit to look around
to see
what you're talking about.
And then if we have to have a public hearing, there's a time limit between
the submission of the application and public hearing.
If there is not a public hearing required, then we've got another time limit on that
that we would go through.
But it's a matter of, you know, several months,
I would say two to four months
process,
you know, depending upon whether the public hearing is in there
to get an answer.
And again, the answer is not going to be no.
We might have to
negotiate
some
changes
so that we can get to yes.
But
that
should all be doable.
Can't see anything that would
prevent us
from getting there. If you said you didn't want to install a sprinkler system
in the temple,
that might be your showstopper.
Think you would be inclined to put in the sprinkler system to protect the attendees,
and that would be the answer to that one. So I think,
you know, all of the applications have a little give and take in it, but
generally we get to the desired outcome
to the satisfaction of everybody.
I would think we could in this case as well.
You very much. So do you have any other questions? Do you have any other questions for us before we let you go?
Have a Yeah, question,
>> go for it, Vanessa. Yeah, okay. So a couple of questions.
Site plan approval,
do we have to meet your section 23,
basically full blown site plans,
signed
by a licensed land surveyor and a PE.
Is that
the way you.
>> That is
yes,
with the project
of this size,
there's a lot of
significance to building a temple. It's not like
if
we were to put a shed in somebody's backyard, we might not go through all 57
items in there. If there are things in that checklist, and there's a checklist
of,
you know, 57 things that the site plan approval or special permit
application form that you don't think you should have to go do,
that's where you go and discuss that with agent Halsey.
And then, you know, he
yes or no based on that and,
you know, he comes to sell the Commission on
why he thinks he agrees with you that you don't need to do that. So there's probably some things in there that you wouldn't have to do, but we would be looking for a
fairly
professional
application to come in that
we would be acting on.
>> One
last question.
For
the site plan approval,
is there a public hearing
and
who makes that decision?
>> If we feel
that we need to have a public hearing, the Commission has the right
to hold one.
There is not a public hearing required
for a site plan approval.
Right.
>> If you take a path that like,
if you look under the historic preservation
section
and going out on a limb a little bit here,
it talks about there are ways to have a special permit in the historic
sites
that is different than what would be normally expected for that business zone.
We could do that with special permit.
The church is a function that
is authorized for site plan approval
in the business zone.
So right off the top of my head, I am guessing that we don't have to have a public hearing,
but we might choose to have one based on what we see the site plan looking like and whether or not we thought there was concern about the neighbors and that sort of thing.
But
that's something
not required, might be warranted based on
the application
that we see that comes in.
But you have no neighbors,
which is really good.
Yes.
>> Thank you.
Any other questions for the commission before we let you go?
>> No, thank you so much for having us. If all of this works out, even though we may not have adjacent neighbors, we're sort of hopeful that we'll be good neighbors to everyone in Andover.
Whatever
plans we come up with, they'll be very thoughtfully done and intentional with sort of a long term view as opposed to something done shoddily in
the short term, because we've sustained our monks and our community is thriving and we're sort of doing well as it is and this will just be sort of a much needed
next stage for
all of us. So thank you. Thank you, Jed and thanks, Jim. Thanks all of you.
>> Thanks for the presentation. Of
course. Look forward to working with you. It was very good.
Take care.
>> Bye. Thank you. Thank you.
Okay.
The next item under new business
is a report discussion item, blight citation ordinance.
And Jim, you were going go through that?
>> Yes.
Town
meeting the other night with a number of ordinances,
I believe 17 of them,
possibly more,
one of which was
a revision to the existing
light ordinance
specific changes included
redefining
what felt underneath.
Blight.
And it included trees and
dead trees
and
it
expanded sort of
the definition of junk to include
a lot of things that just simply don't work.
In addition,
there's actually the ability to cite
for the
light enforcement officer, who happens to be me,
to cite folks,
and impose
fine,
a fine.
This involves a public hearing officer be appointed,
which could
overrule any citation.
What I wanted to point out is that this is sort of
I I don't have a lot of information on this. I I sort of brought in towards the end, but my understanding is
this is potentially a precursor to
using the citation mechanism
for
things,
such as weapons,
and actually
violations
issued by the state police officer on town roads.
Think
what I understood it to be representative was that,
what it's like we wanted to just kind of feel it out and see how it was working
before they expanded
the citation
ability of or the application
of the citation.
That's
about all I have, but I'd be happy to answer any questions if I can.
>> Any questions for Jim on the Blight Ordinance or the citation process?
>> Hi, this is Leanne. I just have a couple comments.
Go ahead, Leanne.
>> Jim, that's interesting. That's the first time I've heard that expressed
that way about what you just said about some of the other items in town.
Just so other people know,
a couple of comments about this in general and the whole process.
I was at the town meeting and spoke against this ordinance.
Jed and Jim were there. I don't know if any of the rest of the members or alternates were there and I didn't see you or haven't met you yet.
For a couple of reasons, just
for your information,
I think that this
ordinance is overkill.
I said that in my remarks, did speak out at the town meeting.
A couple of the selectmen for a couple of reasons. It's such a small town. I think this kind of thing could be handled on a case by case basis, which I also said at the meeting.
In addition, a couple of the selectmen spoke out in reference to a specific property in town
that they want to have quote teeth on quote, which was their word to address.
That might be fine except that we already have an abandoned building ordinance.
If that was their concern, I don't know if it would fall under that or not, but they did set a specific property,
that they wanted to use forward,
but
obviously it's not just that property, it would be anybody in town. And again, I think it's just too much. Another thing I want to mention is that this commission was not brought in on this.
So as some of all of you know,
we put forth a proposed flight ordinance several years ago. It was pretty soundly defeated at a public hearing.
And
I don't think that we were this was on our agenda that we were consulted since the Selectmen started this process over the summer.
I listened to one of their meetings, I believe it was May. Scott, I don't know if you remember which meeting was which, but, another selectman brought up a certain property in town, not the one I was just referring to that had a hole in the roof and he had a concern about that being a safety issue.
And then somewhere along the line,
this
draft ordinance, which was passed
came about.
I don't if it came from, you know, the town attorney. It came from somewhere. So just so you know, those are my concerns
and observations.
>> The whole ordinance and all the ordinances were drafted by
our attorney.
Okay.
>> And they were
drafted, this particular ordinance was drafted because
the
ordinance that we have now has no teeth
and
we have liens on different properties in town and it still doesn't do anything
And they needed to get something
so that we could get some of these properties
straightened out in town.
>> No.
I read the advantage,
property ordinance today and I don't have it up on my screen now, but is there no mechanism right now for the zoning enforcement offered officer to actually
accomplish anything other than.
>> Oh, they send them letters, they sent them letters, Leanne and they and
I'm pretty certain that a couple different properties owe the town.
The town has liens now on those properties
and they're still not doing anything with them.
So, you know we needed to do something
to
get some teeth and
be able to
try to straighten out these properties once and for all.
>> Well, I mean, for
explaining that. Again, I think
it just appears to me that again, a couple of things. One, the commission wasn't consulted
and two,
we
I'm not sure why
the select matter that we'll call it the town
can't address this.
Again, don't know the whole legal process, but can't address this without having
ablite ordinance that applies to the whole town. I understand you have to have somewhere to start from.
>> I guess I know what's coming up with Yeah. Places in Townley and that have,
could have done something with the last ordinance and you know you send letters to everyone and nobody does anything.
Jim you know that
John Valenti sent out a bunch of letters
sent them all fines and they still don't do anything.
>> Is there anything in the statutes that lets us have some more again with
or without a blight ordinance when
letters are sent out by the zoning enforcement agent?
No. I don't know of any.
>> Don't know if any. It falls to civil litigation
bringing the town attorney.
Yeah. But the citation That's allows
what happens? Yeah.
The citation ordinance
bypasses that.
Sorry. It bypasses
what?
>> The need for litigation. The need to draw bring the town attorney into
into the process. I I'm not saying that they wouldn't ever be drawn in, but but on
they don't need to be, you know,
on a simple case by any means.
>> Okay.
Well, thanks again. I guess my only other comment is I'm not sure.
I I appreciate what Jim just said about the difference between litigation
with a town attorney and bypassing
that, but I guess my only other comment is I'm not sure why that wasn't addressed
in 2017
under the
building ordinance.
I understand that that's not exactly the same thing as a flight ordinance, but again it's
that's just.
>> The other ordinance only addressed, you know,
actually safety
issues
with structures
and people getting in them that
addressed the roofs and making sure that all the windows and doors were
closed off,
the roofs were
covered over,
it was more like a safety thing.
>> The way I saw it Leanne was
that
the previous
blight ordinance, we were not successful.
And I'm not
100%
sure
that we've got enough teeth in the one that we just crafted. We'll have to see
how it goes.
But
there are certainly a couple of places that should be addressed.
And I think we need to
I know the,
I think it was Jeff Murray or maybe
Adrian was talking about, we're trying to crawl, walk, run. You know, we're trying
something out here to see how it goes and then build on that,
you know.
But there's a couple of places around town that I'd be happy if we had success, we at least have to have a framework so that we can handle each of those cases
on a case by case basis. I don't think,
you know, the average person in the town
has
got to be overly concerned about
overreach. I could be wrong on that.
And that's why we have
that other process by
if you think that you have been cited in error,
there's a process by which you as the
property owner can go and have somebody hear your case and give
you a chance to make your case and
resolve that.
I
thought it was okay,
but
it's kind of like
we put some lake regs into effect. I know there were some people who thought the lake regs were too strict.
My concern is that they're not strict enough, and we're going to have to go make them more strict because I'm not sure that they're having the desired effect yet.
And it's going to take a while before we figure that out, but
I thought it was an okay step forward.
>> Okay, well, said what I was gonna say. Thanks. Okay.
>> I'm going to move on.
And hopefully this won't take too long. The next item on the agenda is
proposed amendments to the zoning regulation.
And Abby, if you can allow me to share my screen.
You should be able to now.
>> Okay. And
now, if I was on
no, I don't think I can
split screen and share
and get two documents up at once.
But
I think I sent
everybody should have seen this little table
with what I was proposing
that we change.
And I don't want to shortchange
the discussion
at all.
I
can certainly,
I guess,
so everybody's got this.
I've got a copy in front of me. What I will do,
unless somebody has a better idea,
is I'm going to call up the markup copy of the regs and just scroll through the different articles.
And we can talk about what we changed and why. Some of them are very easy.
Most of them are pretty easy. So I don't think it'll take too long.
I just thought I could share two screens at once and I think that's
certainly beyond
my capability
at this point. So we're going to try.
>> Jed,
if I could suggest most of these seem to be, you know, administrative
really, not material changes.
Would it make sense to just go over the ones that
have a material impact?
>> Well,
yes. We'll
do some of that.
And so
I'm going start out with 4.9.2.
And this is, you know, in the definition of rear lot, I changed the word wick to frontage. Very
minor change
and probably,
as Steve just said, not worth
saying a lot about. What I am concerned about, and any of you folks that can back me up just a little bit, is you're reviewing through the regs. If you see someplace else in here,
I didn't change very many places to talk with the frontage, only two.
And I thought I would have to do more than that. And I'm
trying to make sure that when we have the next
contentious discussion about
if a lot's the right shape or not, that I've got all the
corrections made because we wanted to go with frontage.
I'll say no more on that.
I won't
say anything about four eleven(two) that just got rid of the little c because there is no c to make that correct.
I'm going to go down to 10.7
here. Let's see.
Because the first one was what we were talking about. We wanted to do to get
frontage.
The second thing we wanted to do was not be building in the flood prone district.
And so,
down here,
we in Hendy Road, we had
somebody who wanted to build
a house in a flood prone district.
They went to the zoning board of appeals
who
they argued
while our
regulation did not allow building in the flood prone district,
if you look here under specific standards for residential construction, it talked about new construction.
So if it said new construction,
obviously that meant you should be able to build in flood prone district.
We talked about this as a commission afterwards,
and we thought that we did not want people to build in the flood prone district
new construction houses. So I just crossed that out.
Now, if you've already got a house in the flood prone district and you want to improve it, you can do that and there's some rules you need to follow.
But the Commission
conveyed to me that we thought that
we didn't want new construction being built in the flood prone district.
Is there any comment on that particular
point at this time?
>> My
thought is, I'm looking at that, the next one, number two, is manufactured
homes.
That would be also a new construction if that came in. So is that something that needs to be changed also? Well, and that is why I eliminated that whole paragraph.
>> Because
as you just said, if
it's a manufactured home,
that would be a new construction thing. Since we weren't going to permit new construction in a flood prone zone, I just got rid of that whole paragraph. I didn't realize that whole paragraph there. Yep, so we got rid of that one.
And then I tried to
repaginate
the different numbers here,
and I'm going to save that for Abby to do because I worked on it longer than I did the rest of these changes and couldn't get the different numbers to line up there. So that was that for me. But that
was the change that we wanted to make
on the flood prone zone was to eliminate the ability to build a new construction house.
And I think we've done that.
I'm going to move on
to our little chart. And all I did here was I crossed out width and I put frontage.
And there were a couple of different places where
we
do need width, like when we get into the rear lots in that,
but that is covered elsewhere
in all of these different things going down through here were frontage along the road, and I thought frontage was the right term to put in there. So that is that change.
>> Jed, I believe April
also needs to be locked with change to furniture.
>> Okay,
we'll go back to that after we get down to the end, And
if I forget, and I just marked it down on my sheet, remind me and we'll go back and do that. Thank you.
The next couple
are changes that I wanted to discuss
based on our kennel discussions.
And that's
So,
of the commission members may have been a little confused
at the last meeting.
I know I was,
not everything was really clear.
When we came to the meeting, I thought I had a good rationale for not holding a public hearing based on the fact that we had a public hearing before.
Our attorney
didn't tell me whether or not he agreed with my rationale, but he said, here's my rationale.
If we went through
the special
requirements and what to do the application procedure,
it didn't talk about holding a public hearing or having a special permit in here like it did in a B kennel or a Charlie kennel.
Even though I said, well, up here,
it said special permitted uses type A kennel, which to me means
special permit.
The attorney said, yeah, well, I just read the application procedure
and you didn't have to do it for that.
And I was happy with the outcome of our discussion.
But
as I thought about it after,
I wasn't sure that I wanted anybody put in a kennel
anywhere
without a public hearing and the opportunity for the public to weigh in on that.
Scott Beebe had 200 acres of land out there in the middle of nowhere.
I wasn't concerned,
and we had ten years of experience, that he had no complaints about the noise from the kennel
with the neighbors.
But if we did not make
a Class A kennel
have a special permit in a public hearing,
anybody with three acres or more, no matter where that was at, had the right to have a Class A kennel and put housing for 10 dogs there.
I didn't think that was the right way to go. And if somebody were building a kennel next to me, I'd like to have the opportunity to
discuss
that and weigh in on that to make sure that it wasn't going to bother me too much. So I added the words
that
were right the same as the B and C kennel.
The commission will set a public hearing date in accordance with the provisions of the Connecticut general statutes.
So that that would,
going forward, the next guy who comes in and says I want a class A kettle,
we would have to go with the special permit and we'd have to have a public hearing.
Of the Commission members
have any comments on that thought process?
Okay, I'm going to move down to
whoops, 19.1.6,
I did something. Oh.
Okay, so
this talks about parking spots.
And it just referenced an article that didn't have anything to do with parking spots. So I said this section, and that was that. So think that makes that
workable.
Okay,
so we're still under the Class A.
Commission shall take any such action applicable in accordance with Section 6.2 of these regulations,
which talk about the time limits for holding a public hearing, making a decision following the closing of the public hearing, and all that stuff.
And nineteen point four three was again changed
the reference number to
the right thing.
Okay, so if there's no other concerns about kennels, I'm going to go down to
the special permit process.
And that was the last couple of things that we have not talked about before.
Okay, so this said,
currently our procedure says that we are going to notify
property owners who own adjacent land with certified mail.
Our attorney says that's not required and I don't know all the work that Jim has to do to do certified mail,
but
it makes his life a little easier with the certificate of mailing because
of all that. And so I just got rid of that point.
If anybody
has a concern about that, let me know.
But the next one came in to
play on
an
application we did not approve,
and our instruction says the Commission shall state on the record the reasons for its action
and shall publish notice such actions
as required by Connecticut General Statutes.
When I was concerned that we failed to do that,
the attorney branch said, oh, you shouldn't be doing that anyhow.
Because if we put
anything
in our minutes about the specific reason for disapproving
an application, when we disapprove it
and we get
challenged in court on that,
the judge would only look at the reasons we put
in our write up for reasons for refusal
to decide whether or not
we were correct.
If we don't do that, and it's not required by the Connecticut statute that we do,
then the judge has to go back and review the entire case
to see whether or not we were
proper
in
the
determination that we came up to.
So that just protects us a little bit
so that
if we didn't do that and somebody said, well, your procedure says you had to, even though the Connecticut
state statute says you don't,
then we'd probably lost that for not doing that. So that's the reason that I got rid of that words. Then it's just fine tuning a little bit, but that's
what I like to do when we actually use the procedures and we find out there's a little thing in there that's not quite right, we'll keep it down and when we get a bunch of them, we'll go and talk about those.
So, there any whoops, yep,
so I'm going to go back to 4.9.3.
Okay.
Each real eye
shall comply with all requirements.
Yes.
So Kevin, you were saying we changed this width to
>> frontage. Yeah,
because the intent is that we're gonna use frontage now instead of lot width, right? Yep.
>> And I can't
correct why I'm on screen this way. And so
I will
adjust that one and add that to our list there.
>> And then there's a couple other spots too.
The building setback line definition.
Do you have an article number on that?
>> It's down in the definitions
for building setback line. Oh, okay. So under
section 23 or whatever?
Yeah.
>> Any other definitions back there, Kevin? So then would we be removing the lot with definition and adding a frontage definition?
>> I
will go and look somewhere.
I'm not sure of the answer on that. And we wrestled with
frontage seemed intuitively obvious to me until it isn't.
But when we were working on the Pine Ridge application,
because it was a very small driveway back there,
you know, we concluded that frontage had to be
as measured
at the road. So if you got a little curvature in there, it's not just
the distance between the two parallel sides of the driveway. You've got it a little bit bigger
frontage because it's distance alongside the road.
That definition
is in here someplace.
And it agreed with what we came up with. I just can't tell you where it is right this minute.
And I don't want to remove the width definition
because as we talked to Attorney Branch going through this, he said,
maybe you want to have width and frontage.
Both of them there, yep. For odd Yeah, gauge
>> because if you have a lot on a skew, then you could have someone with a 45 degree skewed frontline and then they have a ton of frontage, but very little, but then, you know,
>> of the width. Now, it turns out, there is a lot that is just like that that's for sale on Lake Road right now, right where, no, Lakeside Drive meets School Road.
It's got a lot of frontage because it goes around a very pronounced
curve,
and then it goes back to a point in the back. So it's got a lot of frontage, goes to a point.
And I haven't really decided,
well, that's an existing lot, so it doesn't make any difference.
But if we were to
change the rules so that when we're designing lots, we make them all rectangles.
Or should we
allow
a funny shaped lot?
Or should we make our
regs require rectangles and somebody goes to the zoning board of appeals if they wanted to,
you know, they had a piece of property that
didn't make that, they could go to the zoning board of appeals, state their hardship, and maybe get a
variance.
Anybody got any comments
on that one way or the other?
>> I think it would be incredibly difficult to do pure rectangles.
I think it's got to
some compromise.
>> And that's why I was going to leave the definition of lot width in our regulations.
And
I wasn't
I didn't feel smart enough
to act on that one way or another. I knew we wanted frontage requirements,
but I wasn't sure we wanted to get rid of all the width discussion there.
And maybe give us a little flexibility.
>> Okay. At first, I thought your intention was to swap, to get rid of it completely and just Nope. I just want to put a frontage requirement on all the lots that we design
>> or applicants
come and propose. Got it. So that's what I'm trying to do there.
>> Good. Can I just suggest that we keep in mind that we have the open space
subdivision
provision, which really encourages flexibility,
which
I really think
you wouldn't want to lock into a rectangular lock?
>> Well,
it wouldn't have, yes.
I
hear what you're saying. And if you had a huge lot, like a seven acre lot,
it can be just about any shape you want. You've still got adequate
frontage and width. But
as we have not wrestled with that
in any kind of negative
fashion yet,
I think our
if we incorporate
frontage for all of our lots,
that was the only intent I had to do. That was my only intent at this point.
So,
so that's what I did.
>> In the space requirements chart, would you want to have a, add a column so that you had width and frontage listed in that?
>> I,
We may go that way. I wasn't
ready to have that discussion yet. That's fair.
Next piece is
I was going to wait until we had a
public hearing for some other reason.
There's nothing that says we can't hold a public hearing in November
and get all these changes. I'm not sure there's anything so significant that we
need to have these changes implemented
soon.
But my general thought would be once a year, we
go through the list of all the
little changes that we've discovered
through the years' worth of operations and make a bunch of administration stuff, which is what I think we really got here.
Anybody got any thought on that?
Should we go to public hearing next month or should we wait until we have an opportunity
for another one coming along? I have a comment.
>> Ahead, There
is a
notification requirements of both
budding towns and regional planning agencies or council
governments. And I believe it's sixty days or sixty five days.
>> I think you're right. For zoning changes. I don't know where that is written down, but I remember
that we struggled with that on the Lake Ranch.
>> Yeah,
it's writing statutes.
And the other thought I have is,
if it's very possible that the subdivision regs allude to specific sections of the zoning regs, which would have to be changed in conjunction
with the zoning changes.
>> I'm not sure that I changed anything here
that would
carry Yeah,
I will look.
>> Yeah, take a look. And if there's something there. So
I guess my takeaway is
we will not take any action on this tonight.
But I've got all these. I will add a couple that Kevin mentioned.
Jim, I know you were talking at one point about trying to take the
fees out of our regulations because they're all wrong.
And
if we get a list of those, we can add to this and do it.
I don't want to go through the administrative burden of notifying the additional adjacent towns and
the
capital region
and all that stuff for
little changes when we should be waiting until we have a bunch. But I know there's been some desire to get
the frontage and the
flood prone zone
updated.
So I went off and did that and
>> we'll head on down our merry way. Thank you for doing that too, Jay.
>> You're welcome, Scott. Thank you for being that little pride to keep me honest.
Okay,
well, so I think that's all we'll do here. And I will update
a couple of things that we talked about. Jim, if you find other things, take a look at the subdivision regs.
And we'll talk about it again next month to any additions or corrections.
And then we'll send it off to
do whatever
reviews
that you need to have the other folks do before we take it to public hearing.
At some point, after we're happy with it, I'll run it by our attorney too, just so he gets a cut.
And
yeah, I really thought we were gonna have sign regs to talk about and we do it all with the public hearing for the sign regs. But anyhow, we do have a start there.
I'm going to stop sharing for now.
Next item on the agenda is approval of the regular meeting
for calendar year 2022.
Okay.
So,
was what I put together and I followed the
current
what our bylaws
say is we'll meet on the third Monday of the month.
As this past year,
January and February, the third Monday
is a federal holiday,
and so I moved the date to the fourth Monday.
I stuck with Mondays because Monday for me is town meeting day. Inland Wetlands meets on Monday,
we meet on Monday, a lot of other
Monday meetings, and so
I keep my calendar clear of Mondays for nothing but town meetings.
That doesn't mean we
can't change the bylaws and do something different if this is a hard spot for anybody.
But this is what I was looking at for
the coming year. I guess the only other month that's worth noting is, again, just like this year, we've got a planning and zoning meeting on Monday before Thanksgiving.
And I think that's better than the Monday after Thanksgiving,
so I left that as it was.
Any comments on
that schedule?
Okay,
>> hearing none,
I'll make a motion to approve the schedule as posted. I'll second that. Okay. Thanks, Scott. Any other discussion?
All in favor say aye.
Aye. Any
>> opposed?
Any abstentions?
Motion carries five-zero-zero.
Okay, the next item
is
the Planning and Zoning Commission endorsement of the multiuse path along Route 316.
And
I sent out this presentation
The town has been working on and
went to
in Abby, I forget
what
was that presentation we had that Saturday afternoon?
It was by Sustainable CTE Committee.
>> Right. And so there were a bunch of people that talked about a lot of different things going on.
Ed, what's Ed's last name?
Jerisling.
>> Talked about, he gave, went through this presentation that I sent out to all of you. I won't go through it in
detail now. Ed offered to come to the meeting tonight and
walk us all through it. I told him I didn't think that would be necessary.
Anybody who's
ridden a bike or walked
along 316
with those curves there,
you know, to try and connect,
whether it's you're coming off the rail trail,
the Center Street
to get across to,
you know, the ball fields on the other side of Route 6.
You know, if you do any riding on Route 316, you know that's not a good deal.
And
Eric Anderson is trying to
submit a grant that would get some funding
because it's fairly expensive for a portion of Route 316 to have a little multiuse path away from the road so you don't have to be on that.
So here's
the letter
that I was going to
submit
on behalf of
the Commission
saying that we supported that plan. We've been working on it for over forty years trying to get all the streets so that it's more than just cars driving on it, that people can safely bike and walk and hike around town with the ultimate goal to kind of connect
the
East Side Of Route 316 with the West Side Of Route 316 and have a little community center in there and it connects up safely. So
that's
what I drafted. I just thought I would run it through the Commission and
get any feedback from you folks on that before I send it off to Eric to support his trying to get a grant.
>> Okay. You want a motion for that? I do want a motion for that then. Yep, Scott. I motion to approve the
letter from Planning and Zoning Commission to approve the multi use plant
track along
Route 316.
Second.
>> Thank you, Steve.
Any other
discussion before we vote?
All in favor say aye.
Aye. Any
opposed?
Any abstentions?
And the motion carries five-zero-zero.
Okay. Now I'll stop share.
Next item on the agenda is the approval of the minutes from our meeting of 09/20/2021.
And I will make a motion that the meeting minutes from 09/20/2021
be approved.
Looking for a second.
I'll second it.
>> That was you, Scott? Yep. Okay, thank you. Any discussion on the minutes?
I guess my only discussion on the minutes and I didn't look real hard, Abby,
but I could not find even a typo going through there. I
thought very nicely done.
Thank you.
>> And
with that,
I'll call for a vote. All in favor say aye. Aye. Any
opposed?
Any abstentions?
This is Leanne. I abstain. Okay.
>> And the motion
passes five-zero-one
with Leanne abstaining.
Next item on the agenda is correspondence.
Jim, we have anything there?
No.
Okay.
Going on to administrative reports enforcement actions.
>> Pretty busy in the building office, a lot of construction going on this time of year.
A lot of accessory structures, lot of
building
and
trying to come to grips with the new
permitting
program
and
looking at
perhaps new staff,
a new hire in the very near future.
Enforcement,
to work with
Mr.
Steve Barnett on Route 6.
He's moved some things, but now he's looking at the, and I have not brought him to the
new blight ordinance to his attention as of yet,
will certainly
cover some few of the items he has out there
in front of his property.
Other than that, I just I'm open to questions.
>> How do you think that
new permitting system is working, Jim?
>> It it's difficult to I mean, part of the problem is
well,
I I think it'll work fine. I just haven't
figured it out. I don't work with it enough. You really have to work with something like this regularly.
I think it'll work out fine in the long term. Just or
just short term, it's it's a little problematic for me, but I'll get over it. Yeah. I think it's a good idea. I think it was a good decision,
as much as I hate to say that.
>> Any other questions for Jim?
Hearing none, I'll move on to
item 11,
Commission discussion and miscellaneous.
And I'll start out with one miscellaneous
topic that
I started talking to Jim about that back in June, we approved a six month extension to the gravel pit operation. Oh, yes.
So I
started thinking that I hadn't seen a lot of activity
going on over there recently,
and maybe we should start working on the
extension
again.
And I'm going to let Jim
discuss what conversation he's had with Chris
>> Bell. Yes. I should have brought this up and I forgot quite honestly.
I did have a brief discussion
with Chris Bell, the engineer for,
Genervisis,
the owners of the gravel pit.
And they were at
one point looking at extending
the
removal of gravel,
closer to the
the gas
station,
but needed permission from the owner and could not find him. I think he's
for whatever reason. So
they just basically dropped out of it. But I was assured that
they had a new operator there, a new removal contractor,
and that they would plan to be done
in a three week time period. If you looked at your
report
that was actually just posted today, believe.
I believe two or three loads were removed last week.
But nonetheless, somebody is back on-site.
And I was told is if they're not done
by
within their allowed time period, they're just not gonna remove
they're just gonna leave it as is. That does not take into account the remediation. So I will
be in contact with with them regarding that. I mean, had right now, I believe they have until the end of December. They had a six month
extension from the end of
from
July 1.
>> Right. Because they said that they were gonna bring it to the
to one grade.
Right.
>> I think
concern as a commission is that when we started down the path of allowing the gravel pit there,
we had an understanding of what the site would look like
when it was restored.
And if there is some thought that that's not what the applicant
intends to do,
you know, we should be
hearing
from Chris Bell so that
we can start on that discussion
on what
he does think is going to be and
how we get him to make it look like what he said he was going to do.
>> Okay. I I will speak to him this week and and make sure he's
he's got our November
meeting on his calendar.
Okay.
Jim?
Yes.
>> This is Leanne. Could you repeat did you say that they they can't
locate, if that's the word you used, the actual owner? Or we had discussed in the past that there's somebody whether or they're there, you know, five days a week,
kind of oversee the property. Which person is it that they couldn't locate?
>> It's the owner of the property with the guest. It's Marshall Martin who owns the the property upon which the extra month sits.
>> Okay. So he still owns the whole thing
for for what we're concerned with? Well,
>> no. Marsh Marshall Martin sold the
the auto parts facility to the Genovese.
Right. But he retained ownership to the property upon which the extramarate sits.
And the gravel pit was
purchased
from merits
by
Genesis.
>> Okay. So Marshall Martin just owns the property where the Extremart is? Correct.
And so what is the
>> And over auto parts and the
all the excavation area that's been under
under this topic all this time?
Can you say that again?
>> So
Marshall Martin owns the Extramart location.
Correct. I'm I'm I'm asking you. And then He owns the land. Leases own Andover Auto Parts and the area
where the excavation is.
>> Yes. They purchased it
sometime before they came in with the application.
>> And
so why do they have to get ahold of Marshall Martin?
>> Because,
well,
I think it's
in our regulations. Well,
Chris seemed to think that
he needed his permission if he went within 50 feet of his property line. Quite frankly, I didn't look it up. I was going to wait until I found out if they he didn't seem to think he was going get ahold of Marshall, so I didn't get around to it.
I figured if he
did, then I would look it up.
>> Okay. So Jim, are you saying that just to backtrack for a second, they've taken out x amount of
travel or something and then they don't they haven't taken out more now to remediate. Was that the question? Because they haven't reached Marshall Martin?
>> No. They would have needed Marshall Martin's permission to
expand
to to take out more than they originally had approved. It would have required a modification to the plan.
>> Okay, so it would be to take out more, not less?
>> Correct.
Okay, thanks. It was the 50 feet. It was the materials sitting within 50 feet of his property.
>> Okay, so I guess I said the same thing in two different ways, but you answered that. Alright, thanks. So so Jim, they're they're saying that there's gonna be a mound
>> left there.
If unless Marshall Martin gives the permission to remove it?
Yeah.
>> Yes. That's how I understand you. I will take another look at the plan.
>> That I don't think that anybody on the commission would have ever
would have ever thought that it wasn't ever gonna be anything but at one level.
>> Yeah. I I understand what you're saying, and and you're right. I mean, it it
>> doesn't make sense. We're gonna be leaving a little peak in one spot there.
>> And that's the other thing that doesn't make sense is he's concerned about modifying
the permit to take moreover
by the Extramart.
We want him to just remove that big mound of material
he's got out there like he said he was going to do. Just want him to execute
>> the permit that he's got. It wasn't that he was looking for the He was looking to provide a more complete marketable site.
It wasn't really
the additional material they were looking at. But yes, and he's
well aware that we
do have to
he does have to bring it back to the commission to
alter that
tension plan which was discussed.
>> Where did this ever come up that about the 50 feet?
Who brought He that
>> called me up last week and he just said he might be looking at the possibility of it.
>> He can't find a buyer, is that the only reason you think for
that material?
>> No, no, no, no, no, no.
Was looking at the possibility of
extending
the excavation 50 feet further.
I mean, I did not go back and look at the plan at that point in time. He just said he would get back to me and
>> I'm gonna have to look at the plan now that these questions are raised. Because I would have thought that the 50 foot thing would have the first person that would have brought it up was the Planning and Zoning Commission,
not not the s actual excavator.
Right?
I mean, would, I wouldn't think that he would take all the material he could.
Right. So something's amiss.
>> And that's why I think we need Chris Bell to come.
I will refresh
Refresh my my to the six month extension. With
respect to the plan and the regulations.
>> We we wouldn't have approved
leaving a mountain in the front of there, certainly.
>> Yeah, now they mentioned it doesn't make sense.
I didn't question it when he brought it up. I just kind of was waiting to see what.
What he was gonna do, what he planned to do and I and.
And he would be here.
If that would. If you plan to move forward.
But we have what $25,000
of their money.
I believe so. Yeah,
so that'll do it.
>> Okay, so we'll put the
gravel pit discussion
on the agenda for the November meeting.
Can I ask any other questions? Yep, go ahead, Leanne.
>> Scott or Jim, or probably Jim, is this mound that we're talking about, is this something that's already there that that he he's brought up, or is it something that they've moved
soil or gravel or what have you?
>> This property is and created this. No. It's existing. It it was not created by the by the exclamation
process
of the operation.
>> Okay. So we're gonna leave it that you're gonna try to have a discussion with Chris Bell?
>> Well, I will, and it will also
I will have him attend the next meeting and
have him clarify what he's looking for.
Do you have there when the extension is up?
>> I believe it's the end of December.
It's six months from July 1.
>> And it was for
August, September, October
for six months?
>> Yeah, we voted on that at the June meeting, June 21.
>> Okay.
So we wanna make sure that things are proceeding the way that we want.
Yes.
>> Leanne, that would the 50 feet would probably leave some of that peak there.
It's
not
that wouldn't look very nice.
>> Yeah, I think you're right Scott, I think it is a new issue.
>> It is, we wouldn't have approved it I'm sure they told That's us why I'm questioning why he's saying something about 50 feet where he even came up with that.
>> Right, our expectation was that the lot would be level.
Exactly.
>> And
so now, you know, I'm hearing maybe
that's not true, time to get Chris Bell back here to
help us understand what it is he's thinking the way ahead is.
Go from there.
Okay, any other
miscellaneous topics?
Any feedback from the Commission for me on
how we go through the different items and that sort of thing? Are we doing that in a reasonable manner? I know tonight we referenced no procedures. Last month, we referenced lots of procedures.
I think we didn't have reason
except maybe, you know, should we have looked at a couple of the things that where the requirements come from that
the Pine Ridge development,
you know, has to come back to us so that everybody's clear on that?
What's the thought on how we're doing on going through the meetings? Too much, too little, just right?
>> I
think that every application we should go over some of the regulations,
how they're written to show everybody
exactly how we come upon these answers.
>> Okay,
yeah, I agree with that.
And I think we didn't have any applications really to go through
the procedures with tonight, so we kind of got
a buy on that. But
I know discussions
with some of the members, after we think we're doing that,
you're not
totally,
well, none of us are totally familiar with the procedure yet, but sometimes we still go through them too fast
to make sense. So, I would encourage each of the Commission members
to,
you know,
ask questions as we're going through on why we're doing different things.
And hopefully,
Jim or I will always have an answer,
even if it's I don't know.
We'll try and do better than that,
but that's that. So,
I think we're pretty much on target then.
I guess
anybody from the public left here that wants to talk?
I think
everybody else has gone away.
So I
move that we adjourn. Can we have a second? Second.
Second. Any opposed?
And I appreciate all the members
showing up tonight. We got everybody but Susan here and the
attendance has been very good. I know
sometimes it may not be all that as exciting as we hammer through all this different stuff, but I think it's important to the town
and I appreciate
Abby's great job on getting the minutes and all that stuff
documented as we continue
on our merry way. So with that, I thank you all for participating.
And
so long and we'll see you
in November, the Monday before Thanksgiving, whatever day that happens to be. Which
day was that, Scott? Good night. Good night. That's a good day. Okay. Good day, everybody. Yep. Good night.
Thanks, Jed.